So once we basically get here. Essentially what we want to do is go
to the side of the room, use your email.
once we are in here,
and this kind of loads up.
Essentially I already have instances here, but basically we want to create like a
new virtual machine. So basically we want to do is we are going to
go over to launch instances.
Alright, and so this is pretty much kind of a setup.
So you can call the, you know, your server.
So I'll just call it, you know, just say a mile away.
Server, oh, something like that.
And then we're going to select the type of virtual machine we want.
We're going to go with windows here. It
wants that low. We're going to set the type of instance because we're on
like a free tier account. We're just pretty much looking to kind
of select the type of compute power we want in memory.
So we're just going to pick the highest one in the free tier.
So, so we have this,
two CPU eight gigabyte memory.
Want to select that.
So now we're going to select our basic or key pair.
So this basically authenticates the password that we're going to use.
So we're going to click create key pair.
Uh, we're going to name our key pair and I'm saying my server
one or whatever.
Two. Okay. Oh, one.
So then we're going to create key pair. Now make sure when this when
I keep here downloads that you see. Save it because if you don't save
it, you're not going to be able to get back in your system and
you can use like a, so AWS does have like another way,
to kind of get into your virtual machine in case you lose,
you lose that password. But yeah, make sure you keep that key period there.
So once we do that, we don't really have to do anything in our
network settings. We'll keep that the same, configure the same and all you do
is pretty much loss or instance at that point.
Okay, so once it says successful, we're going to click here.
Okay, so this kind of gives us all the information about our virtual machine
so you can see like as detailed status,
monitoring, these different things. So now I'm going to go over back over to
instances, instances. And we should see our new virtual machine,
initializing. So basically, we need to just kind of wait.
so basically when it does a statistic, we'll say, hey,
three out of three checks have passed. So we'll wait for that.
But, But in the meantime we can kind of launch,
we don't need to, since we don't have to wait,
we'll just kind of launch one of the machines. So essentially once,
you know that my web server O.O.1 is running,
it'll say running, you know, here. and Daniel has this kind of three checks
passed. And Daniel basically is going to want this to start that virtual machines.
So the basic what you'll do is, since I already have a virtual machine
kind of created, so I'm going to select that to my web server.
And then I'm going to go over to instant state and I'm going to
click start instance. And I believe AWS gives you like in a free
account to give you like a hundred dollar credit. so,
so when you're logging into your virtual machines,
make sure to log out so you're not eating up your credit. Okay.
So we basically have to wait for this to start.
this instance is running.
So what we're going to do is go to connect.
We're going to. So, basically,
if you ever lose your, you know, your, your key,
your pass key, you can kind of get into your AWS virtual
machine using this SSM SESM manager.
Um, and I'll probably go over that process another time.
But what we're going to do is going to go through. RDP client.
We're going to go down to get password. We're going to upload our private
key that we just download it.
And then we're going to hit the trip password. And then that will pull
up, populate our password here. We're going to copy that.
And then we're going to go up to download remote desktop file.
We're going to click on that. Here.
So we'll cut. Copy. Drop that in there.
Click OK. So this will say.
So sometimes like, you know, it may not work.
So you may have to stop the instance and rewatch it,
but basically we're just going to click Yes. And this is going to load
our instance. So bring this over here to see it.
Okay. So now we're in our virtual machine. And once you're in,
you can do things like set up action, you know,
active directory, various sort of things. But yep,
that's how we do it in AWS.